<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PSPT</title><link href="https://pspt.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pspt.in/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pspt.in/</id><updated>2018-02-11T19:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Why and What and How is Travis CI</title><link href="https://pspt.in/why-and-what-is-travis-ci/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-11T19:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-11T19:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>PSPT</name></author><id>tag:pspt.in,2018-02-11:/why-and-what-is-travis-ci/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Seems like Travis CI has a lot to offer for TSP&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="what-is-continuous-integration"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Continuous Integration?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is to make sure that code doesn't break at any point of time. The paradigm says to commit the code as frequently as possible to avoid 'merge hell'. These atomic commits along with unit testing will help prevent a lot of problems in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-is-travis-ci"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Travis CI?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps in testing commits from many developers. Lets say there are many persons working on your code. A new person commits a new code without testing his version. If the new code breaks then the Travis CI will show the error and help us to sort out the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I faced this issue when I tried adding new code to pelican theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-to-travis-ci"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to Travis CI?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very straight forward. The following are required:
- version control
- tests.py file
- .travis.yml file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My example of &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;tests.py&lt;/tt&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;...code:: python&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;import unittest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="last docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;def test_one_plus_one_two:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;return assertEqual(1+1, 2)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;if __name__ == &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot;:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;unittest.main()&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...
My example of &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/tt&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...code::yaml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;langauge: python
python:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;script: python tests.py&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thats it. You can now push it to github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travis CI will take care of all your requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="CI"></category><category term="documentation"></category></entry><entry><title>A few failures</title><link href="https://pspt.in/a-few-failures/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-08T22:19:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-08T22:19:00+05:30</updated><author><name>PSPT</name></author><id>tag:pspt.in,2018-02-08:/a-few-failures/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Failures are the stepping stones of success&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Again to stress my point, this blog is for documenting things. This post is a small intro to the pre TheSciPost Era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="speranz-era"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Speranz Era&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was always obsessed with websites and internet. The way these two words changed the world is mind boggling. In my first year, I wanted to start a travel booking service. It was in the year 2013 and I didn't even posses a laptop for working on my idea. So, I borrowed laptop from Prudhvi and started reading all the posts related to starting a website. The conclusion was to learn coding for DIY or to hire a coder for that big project. Hiring a coder was not my cup of tea, so the idea didn't really takeoff.
But something else was about to happen in my life. I started to learn coding. I as a student was also my own guru. Soon, I've learnt HTML and CSS. I started experimenting on different templates that were available for free on internet.
In the December of 2013, my father brought me a laptop and this little instrument completely changed my life. Wordpress was the tech stack behind my first website learnforfun(.)org. By the end of my first year, there was nothing new to learn from Wordpress. After all this ease of use had made Wordpress popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a sophomore, I started a new website Speranz. Again this was a failure. But I have learnt a lot of lessons from this startup. The following are a few takeaways that come on top of my mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There cannot be more managers than actual workers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't make partnership with lazy people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't make partnership with people who boast about themselves or the so called narcissists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persistency is the key to success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Without patience there is no business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trust among the partners is very required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There cannot be many people than required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't go for cheap raw material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Milestones are very important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vision and mission are important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enthusiasm should stay even in hard times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't make heavy publicity until your product has atleast some value for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going in an organized fashion is very important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Success doesn't come within a day, it takes time - a lot of time!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blame game is very dangerous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each and every partner should contribute something equally for the Startup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delegating all the work on a single person doesn't work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheap publicity will never work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never start a startup just to earn money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also made a lot of mistakes in the journey from start to failure of Speranz. But I am very happy that I've learnt a lot of things in the early stages of my life. By the way, Speranz still has a Facebook page with 1137 likes. To be frank with you, there are around 50% fake likes for Speranz page. On the whole Speranz is now defunct and I'm very that it is a failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="watam-era"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Watam Era&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Names mentioned here are not their full names. I have only mentioned first 3 characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again back to my first year. I was alloted Room No. 616 in N block hostel. In my neighboring room(Room No. 615) was Var. Har my room mate and Var were very close friends. As they posted on their facebook walls - &amp;quot;Brothers from another mothers&amp;quot;. Var got inspired by Aga and wanted to start a T-Shirt printing business. Harish once called me and as if it was a secret that might threaten national security, they both explained me the business model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically the idea was exact copy of Mr. Aga's. When I became a sophomore, the idea really took off. Har and Var went to Thirupur to check upon the suppliers. They called me, but out of fear, greediness and anxiety I told them all sorts of stories to avoid the trip. They went to Thirupur and found some suppliers. I found a few on IndiaMart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Har and Var brought some samples from the suppliers. The sample was a first copy or may be a original one. (It might be that the same supplier is also manufacturing shirts for MNCs.) After Har showed samples to few friends, they all wanted these cheap first copy. We found business in it and sold them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No investment, but we made a handsome INR 5000 profit. Then our first client IEEE RAS. It was Ris behind that scam ;). I organized meetings every day. Har, Var and I talked about the business development everyday. For some of the reasons mentioned in the &amp;quot;lessons I have learnt&amp;quot;, I came out of the business. After that, Watam did supply T-shirts for few clients. Har and Var also requested me to rejoin the business but I didn't want to. &amp;quot;Decision once taken should be final.&amp;quot; Few lessons which I have learnt from Watam are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never make partnerships with people in living relationship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never continue your partnership with a selfish person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never start a business for money. Yeah the same lesson learnt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never trust a person who wants to buy a BMW on the day 1 of the business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality is the most important virtue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vision of where your business will be and how it helps people is very important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a story for your business. Create one if you don't have a story.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participate in free markets to know the reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friends are only your end customers, they cannot be your distributors or free marketing staff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free labor is a hoax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never partner with people who don't have same frequency as yours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never work with people who are desperate about earning money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Yeah! these were the key takeoffs from my startup failures. And also these two were two major startups in my life. I had many other ideas in my life, but they didn't even enter the startup phase, why bother about the failure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="failures"></category><category term="documentation"></category></entry><entry><title>My First Post</title><link href="https://pspt.in/my-first-post/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-07T20:42:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-07T21:07:00+05:30</updated><author><name>PSPT</name></author><id>tag:pspt.in,2018-02-07:/my-first-post/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;First comes only for first time!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first post on this blog. At this point my main aim is to document all the business related and coding related stuff I will be involved in. The concept is &amp;quot;not to&amp;quot; overload it with many things. Hope this will be a very good start for me to document all the things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this post I will start with the post related to TheSciPost. I will explain you the business case and why I wanted to start documenting things. I will try to make the readability below grade 6 so that everyone can understand things easily. I'm writing this post on the Hemmingway app and have used pelican to generate this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh! you may not be seeing the same design and layout because after the main aim of this blog is achieved, I will be porting it to a new design.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="first"></category><category term="documentation"></category></entry></feed>